Nationality: Singaporean Mobile: +852 9858 7886 (HK) / +65 9830 8527 (SG)

Currently residing in: Hong Kong Email: ngxinyao@hotmail.com

SUMMARY

I love investment for the work it entails – exploring, learning about culture and businesses, interacting with respectable executives and experts, having accountability and taking responsibilities. Career goal is to be a top notch Asia-centric portfolio manager. Possess deep regional experience in Greater China and Singapore stock markets across multiple sectors from an enriching career since 2007. Proven track record in consistently beating relevant benchmarks. Articulate communicator in both English and Mandarin Chinese with native fluency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Allard Partners Limited (US\$ 1bn long-only equity fund), Hong Kong

Jun 2015 – Present

Investment Analyst, Investment Strategy & Research Management Department

- Made important contribution to our main fund, Allard Growth Fund, winning best Asia Ex-Japan fund in AsiaHedge Awards 2016 and best long-only Asian equity fund (over 5 years) in AI Hedge Fund Awards 2017.
- Practiced deep, fundamental equity research covering Greater China with strong sense of business-mindedness, inquisitiveness and forward thinking, complemented with competency in financial modelling and financial analysis.
- Integral member of a 3-man Greater China research team, within an 8-man investment team (including a portfolio manager) with flat hierarchy that gives every analyst a strong say on decisions.
- Generalist role that allowed me flexibility to acquire broad knowledge across many sectors, particularly the sectors of internet, consumer, real estate and utilities.
- Investment ideas since joining till 12 Feb 2017 generated 15.9% return on average, significantly outperforming benchmark. MSCI APAC Ex-Japan returned -2.0% over same period with Hang Seng, Shanghai and Shenzhen composites faring much worse.

Central Provident Fund Board (Singapore's pension fund administrator), Singapore

Dec 2010 – Aug 2013

Portfolio Manager, Investment Management Department

- Built and co-managed a Singapore-REIT equity portfolio (AUM > S\$150m), outperformed the benchmark by over 3% (annualised) with a long-term, bottom-up strategy focused on deep fundamental research. Had responsibilities for portfolio management, equity research and trading.
- Led a 3-man team in equity research covering Singapore-REIT sector with strong competencies in financial modelling, valuation and financial analysis. Gained deep knowledge of property sector.
- Also supported research on fund analysis, global macroeconomics and asset allocation in a broad ranging role.

BNP Paribas, Singapore

Sep 2007 - Nov 2010

Analyst, Wealth Management Compliance

- Advised private bankers in customer due diligence to achieve compliance with international regulations.
- Analysed client investment portfolios for investment suitability.

EDUCATION

Fudan University, Shanghai

Sep 2013 – Jul 2015

Master of Business Administration

- GPA: 3.94/4.00
- Awarded Allard Partners Scholarship (sole winner) and Fudan MBA Scholarship (2nd Prize)
- Finished 2nd in AIFA College Financial Modelling Competition 2015 (China nationwide contest).
- Starting member of the MBA soccer team: champions in 2013 and runners-up in 2014 of annual Shanghai MBA tournament.
- Received top grade for dissertation on "Impact of Spinoffs on Equity Values in Hong Kong".

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Jul 2004 – Jun 2007

Bachelor of Business, major in Banking and Finance

OTHER INFORMATION

Languages: English and Mandarin Chinese (native fluency in both)

Certs/Training: CFA Charter (since 2011), Financial Modelling Workshop (Wall St. Training), Intensive Bank

Analysis (Fitch Training), Supervisory Management Skills (NBOGroup)

Software tools: Bloomberg, FactSet

Interests: Reading, soccer, jogging, and food